

HOÀNG THỊ ĐÀO

0962.670.923 | hoangdao1992.dhnn@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/anhdao-hoang-71126720a

Vo Van Ngan, Thu Duc, Ho Chi Minh city

Over the past 6 years of experience in merchandising, production planning, and demand planner position, I've got experience in order management, Factory planning, customer forecast & demand analysis, and inventory management. I'm looking forward to a proactive, professional environment in the field of the supply chain.

Work Experiences

Avery Dennison Retail Branding - Long Hau IP Can Giuoc

Feb 2022 - Present

District, Long An province, Vietnam

(Senior) Demand Planner

- 1. Forecast analyze and supply plan:
- Develop and follow demand forecasts (operational forecasts) at multiple levels of aggregation for multiple time horizons as part of demand planning function
- Manages the Forecast of customer brands. Contribute to developing collaborative forecasts with distributors and internal customers.
- Analyze Material FC & Finance forecase base on historical demand, FC accuracy and feedback sale team to adjust if have any abnormal.
- Closely connects with the Commercial/ Sale team through weekly demand control meetings to quickly reflect changes in the market,
- Make monthly supply plan to guide other dept to prepare capacity to adapt customer demand (setup loading plan, target output) and propose solution to gain the monthly target sale.
- Weekly review and escalete sale high and low intake to make sure the target of finance.
- 2. Factory capacity:
- Working with production team, update the capacity of the production line to have the overall view then have actions plan to match
 demand and capacity to ensure have enough capacity to serve customer's orders per year. (work over time, place orders to outsource
 for supporting in-house capacity, ask support IC...)
- 3. Stock management:
- · Base on historical demand ad sale trend to build stock FG (IBR) to serve for short leadtime orders
- · Weekly review and escalate to sale if have any potential of shortage or over stock.
- Safety stocks target setting based on historical and future demand, control inventory based on target cut off from Supply chain &
 Finance. Based on demand, ensure supply and inventory plans to be balanced and in-line with operating strategy, Customer Service
 Level and propose solution to reach Excellence. Facilitates business in decision making by scenarios simulation.
- · Other tasks:
- Be a main contact between Head Quarter and Vietnam Factory to ensure the accuracy status of demand in each period.
- Pro-actively communicate supply chain issues and provide alternatives...

Thai Binh shoe company - TBS Group - Binh Duong

Oct 2019 - Feb 2022

Merchandiser - Planning team

- 1. Order management:
- Own the execution of the PO management process from receiving in system until shipping out, ensure the timeline delivery and solve all problems relevantly.
- Be responsible for all customer inquiries, checking and responding to their request for all problem-relate orders. Checking and response all changes of PO (date of delivery request, shipment mode...)
- Confirming orders and ensuring the reliability of delivery date. Follow-up orders and demand forecast to ensure the model's
 availability. Analyze weekly exceptions and unconfirmed PO's ensuring the execution of actions to resolve issues
- Collaborate with Supply Chain for timely deliveries and resolve/handle relevant incidents (if any).
- · Manage price referencing to ensure correct pricing in the system.
- 2. Customer demand & Forecase analysis:
- Monitoring component inventory levels, identifying purchasing needs, optimizing components stock ensure reliable data with MRP logic. Collaborate with custom's Zone Demand Planners on updating and monitoring production planning to build stock bases on market intelligence
- Reflect weekly forecast, analyze inventory and shortage to get supply for demand to meet delivery time. Feedback CPM & RS if have any abnormal forecasting.
- Analyzing orders received, future customer demand, and compare with selections for the whole season, and alert customers if there is
 an anomaly with their forecast to ensure no long backlog of Components in stock.
- 3. Factory capacity:
- Be responsible for factory capacity, analyze plan DO in the future to arrange Factory's production Plan to adapt to customer's demand.
- · Weekly checking FTY's WIP to ensure the reasonable of their planning.
- Collaborate with the planning manager to define the production lead time for each model at the beginning of the year.

- Working with planning team to define the allocation (which factory) for each model and booking the FT Y capacity.
- 4. Component management:
- Working closely with RS & CPM from custome zones and analyze future demand to validate CPT purchasing quantity. (Compounent Bought in Advance). (combine with MOQ, surcharge...)
- Collaborate with purchasing team, QA and supplier to ensure on time deliveries, escalation of issues where required
- Monthly checking CPT stock, compare with future demand and alert if have any risk of over STK or quality CPT if it was store over limited time in warehouse
- 5. New model development & seasonal preparation:
- Join into selection result meeting to get over view of all model and quantity selection each season. Discuss with customers to build S&OP and supply methods for each model at the beginning of the season.
- · Get the top-flop meeting for new models and drive solutions to adapt to their demand for them
- Collaborate with the Development team to ensure the timeline of new model processing, Work with the factory to build retro planning
 for a new model, work with component suppliers to push the material on time for retro planning, and ensure the first implantation order
 in store.
- · 6. KPI & projects:
- · Responsible for supply KPI, following up, and, driving improvement action plan with FTY, other teams... to achieve the target,
- Join in a lot of projects with customers: SSE audit, reduce production lead time, supply autonomy, work like as supply production leader as customers...
- · Building SOP & Job instructions for order management tasks and supporting my boss to train new employees

YC TECH company - Binh Duong

Apr 2017 - Apr 2019

Merchandiser - Marketing team

- Order management: Represent my boss to work with customers to solve orders and control orders from receiving to shipping out.
- · Order delivery: Arrange shipment and make sure timely delivery date.
- New Model processing: Making the quotation and joining in the development process of the new model, getting a sample from customers, and confirming the sample with them.
- · Payment: Making Debit notes and following the payment process with the accounting department.
- · Other task: Working closely with warehouse, QA, and production supervisor to ensure our product quantity and quality.
- Making daily reports about shipment quantity and finding solutions to reach the monthly KPI from head office.
- · Training new employees and supporting our co-workers.

Education Level

HA NOI UNIVERSITY OF AGRICULTURE - Ha Noi

May 2011 - Aug 2015

Bachelor Degree in Environmental science, 3.00/4.00

- · Achieve 5 times scholarship.
- · The second prize in scientific research in the university.

Skills, Achievements & Other Experience

- Achievements (2019): The best staff performance in YC tech in 2019.
- Achievements (2020): The first SPL validation by Decathlon in the TBS group.
- · Projects: Supply autonomy project, Production leadtime reduction
- Hard Skills: Microsoft Office skills, Computer skills, Management skills, SAP, prod.com system, Project management skills, Analytical skills, Data report.
- Soft Skills: Time management, Communication, Adaptability, Problem-solving, Interpersonal skills, Negotiation.